So let's find a few data quality issues through visual assessment.
让我们通过目测评估来找出一些数据质量问题
Again, data quality issues are issues with content.
再次重申一下 数据质量问题是内容的问题
And reminder, we've got the patients treatments and
顺便提一句
adverse reactions tables displayed here in our Jupyter Notebook in Pandas' data frames.
我们在 Pandas DataFrame 中的 Jupyter Notebook 中有患者、治疗和不良反应表
So assessment is often guided by what you need to analyze.
所以一般是在了解自己需要分析的内容之后再进行评估
And for this clinical trial data,
对于这项临床试验数据
our key metric is change in hba1c,
我们的关键指标是该治疗表中 hba1c 的变化
or hba1c change in this treatments table.
即表中 hba1c_change 一列
For this new oral insulin called Auralin to be deemed effective,
判断 Auralin 这种新型口服胰岛素是否有效
we need a certain level and mean hba1c change
我们需要一定的 hba1c 水平和 hba1c 平均值变化
compared to the incumbent injectable insulin Novodra.
然后与现有的可注射胰岛素 Novodra 进行比较
So this column definitely has to be clean and it looks like some of
所以肯定需要对该列进行整理
these entries are empty, NaN, missing values.
另外某些条目是空的 显示为 NaN 即非值
Whoever was recording these hba1c start and end levels,
记录 hba1c 开始和结束水平的人
might have just forgot to record the change here.
可能恰好忘记在这里记录 hba1c 的变化
And it's clearly evident in lots of entries.
同样的情况在表中非常明显
So that's one issue we detected already. Let's document it.
这是我们查看到的一个问题 我们来记录一下
I like to separate the issues by quality and tidiness.
将问题分为质量和整洁度两个方面
We'll put this one under quality because it's a content issue.
那么现在这个问题跟内容有关 属于质量问题
So the observation would be something like,
因此观察结果表述为
treatments table missing hba1c changes.
治疗表缺少 hba1c 变化情况
And let's go back to the patients table.
让我们回到患者表
One quick thing you might notice here is the zip code column.
你可能一眼就会注意到邮政编码列
All of the entries here have decimals, point zero.
该列下所有条目都带有小数点 小数点后为零
In some zip codes of five digits before
一些邮政编码在小数点前面是五位数
the decimal and others have four before the decimal.
一些为四位数
So there are actually two issues here.
所以这里有两个问题
One is data type.
一个是数据类型
Zip codes should actually be strings,
邮政编码应该是字符串
not floats, or even integers.
而不是浮点数 甚至不是整数
And the other is that the string should be a length of five characters, rather than four.
另一个问题是 字符串长度应该是五个字符 而不是四个
So this seems like a pretty obvious mistake that no human would really make.
这个错误显而易见 没有人会犯这种错误
So how could this have happened?
那么这是怎么发生的呢？
I think the blame for this one lands on software.
我想这是软件的原因
I'm pretty sure that this data was entered
毫无疑问
initially in a spreadsheet program like Google Sheets,
这些数据最初是在像 Google Sheets 或 Excel 这样的电子表格程序中输入的
or Excel, which probably recognize this column as a number.
后者可能会将此列识别为一个数字
And these programs usually chop off the leading zeros. Like here.
而且这些程序通常会略掉最前面的零 比如这里
It should be 07095.
本来应该为 07095
See, if I type zero and it still won't change to 07095.
看到了吧 如果我输入 0 它仍然不会改变为 07095
So this column isn't as vital to clean as the hba1c change column,
这一列并不像 hba1c_change 列那样重要
but it still could have accurate demographic information,
但仍应反应准确的人口统计信息
especially if the organizer of this clinical trial
尤其是如果该临床试验的组织者
want to send mail to each patient for example,
想要发送邮件给每个患者
and do it in an automated fashion.
例如自动发送
So let's document it now.
所以我们来记录一下
And again, we've got the quality and tidiness separations
在这里有质量和整洁度分类
here and I usually like to put these assessments directly
我通常喜欢将评估
above the clean header because they're easier
直接放在 clean 标题上面
to see when you're actually cleaning and coding down here,
这样当你在下方清理和编码时更容易看清这些评估
rather than scrolling up past all of these tables and
而不需要滚动过所有这些表
looking at the documentation if it was here,
来查看位于这个位置的记录
right below the SS header for example.
比如在 SS 标题下面
So, back to the patients table.
回到患者表
Let's find another issue.
找出另外一个问题
Let's look at this height variable here.
看看这个高度变量
If you scroll a bit, you'll see that there is this entry here for Tim Neudorf.
滚动一下 可以看到 Tim Neudorf 相关数据
His recorded height is 27 inches,
显示身高为 27 英寸
that's two feet and three inches tall.
那是两英尺三英寸高
Given that the inclusion criteria of this clinical trial is 18 years old,
考虑到该临床试验的纳入标准为 18 岁
this doesn't seem like a plausible adult height.
这似乎不是一个合理的成年人身高
And yes, the shortest adult ever was about 22 inches tall.
当然 迄今最矮的成年人约有 22 英寸高
You can also just check with the weight and the body mass index of this person.
也可以检查这个人的体重和体质量
Being 27 inches tall and
27 英寸高
192 pounds is probably not physically possible for a living human.
192 磅重 从生理上来看是不可能的
And the body mass index here at 26.1 BMI.
而体质量指数为 26.1 BMI
BMI can be calculated by multiplying 703,
BMI 可以由 703
which is a conversion factor,
乘以个人体重 (磅)
by an individual's weight in pounds,
703 为转换系数
divided by that individual's squared height in inches.
然后除以个人身高 (英寸) 的平方来计算
And a BMI of 185 is just ridiculous.
BMI 为 185 是非常荒谬的
That human would not be alive.
不可能存在这样的的人
So maybe whoever entered this data switched the digits around by accident,
所以也许有人输入数据时意外更换了数字位置
like put 27 instead of 72.
将 72 输为 27
And yes, that makes sense.
这样还讲得通
This BMI corroborates this BMI on the table here, roughly 26.1.
由 72 英寸的身高得出的 BMI 与表中的 26.1 一致
So again, we'll document that.
同理 我们需要记录下来
This is important in terms of the clinical trial because reporting average metrics,
这在临床试验非常重要
like average height, average weight of each patient,
因为需要报告患者
especially as divided within the two treatment groups Auralin and Novodra.
尤其是两个治疗组 Auralin 和 Novodra 的患者的平均身高体重等平均指标
Ideally, these metrics should be roughly the same so you can compare
理想情况下 这些指标应大致相同
the effectiveness of each drug without being concerned about biases in these variables.
以方便比较每种药物的有效性而不用担心这些变量的偏差
So back to the patients table.
现在再看一下患者表
Let's do some more scrolling.
继续滚动
Some more visual assessment.
做另外一些目测评估
Keep an eye on the state column.
注意患者所在州这一列
This issue here, there's New York and NY.
问题出在这里 New York 和 NY
There are two representations of state,
这是同一个州的两种表达
the full state name and the abbreviation.
分别是它的全称和缩写
This is probably a data entry error by whoever was entering this data into the computer.
这可能是某人在将数据输入计算机时出现的错误
This isn't that big a deal to clean,
虽然算不上什么大问题
but let's do it anyways.
我们依然来记录一下
It's great to have consistent data.
保持数据的一致性很重要
And here's what the observation could look like.
观察结果记录如下
So that's five data quality issues we've
这样一来 我们仅通过目测评估
already identified through visual assessment alone.
就发现了五个数据质量问题